Guide to the Charles Templeman Loram Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Templeman Loram papers
1779-1975
1884-1940
MS 10
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.25
The papers consist of correspondence, articles, reports, notes, lectures, memorabilia, and other papers of Charles Templeman Loram, educator and professor of education in South Africa and at Yale. Included are papers both from his work at Yale and his earlier work as an educational administrator in South Africa. There is also one box of records from the South Africa Native Affairs Commission.
Loram, C. T. (Charles Templeman), 1879-1940
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Charles T. Loram, 1940-1952; and Ian C. Loram, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series and one addition: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Government Records. IV. Miscellaneous. V. Maps. VI. Pictures.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Templeman Loram (1879-1940) Papers document the life work of an internationally famous educator and professor of education in South Africa and at Yale. Most of the seventeen box collection consists of the writings of Professor Loram, his students and his colleagues on a wide variety of topics within the general fields of education, anthropology, religion, and race relations. Over three boxes in the papers consist of notebooks and notes compiled at the University of Cambridge.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Pietermaritzburg, South Africa, Loram was educated at the University of the Cape of Good Hope (B.A. 1900), and the University of Cambridge (B.A. and LL.B. 1905, M.A. 1908), and Columbia University (Ph.D. 1917). In Africa, Loram held a number of government positions in education. Beginning as a teacher at Pietermaritzburg College, he was inspector of schools in Natal (1906-1917), Chief Inspector of Native Education (1917-1920), a member of the Union of South Africa Native Affairs Commission (1920-1929), Chief Inspector of Education, Natal (1929-1930), and Superintendent of Education (1930-1931).
In 1931, Charles Loram was appointed Sterling Professor of Education at Yale University, holding the position until his death in 1940. He also served as chairman and director of studies in the department of culture contacts and race relations in the Yale Graduate School from 1933. Other positions and honors held by Loram include: member of the Phelps-Stokes commission to Africa, 1922, to East Africa, 1925; trustee of Yale-in-China, recipient of honorary M.A. Yale University, 1931, recipient of honorary ED.D. University of Colorado, 1937; and participant in many seminars and conferences on the American Indian, Negroes, Africans, and Pacific Islanders. He was the author of The Education of the South African Native, 1919.
African Americans; Anthropology; Education -- South Africa; Education; Race relations; Religion -- 20th Century; Students; Maps (documents); Clergy; Educators; Loram, C. T. (Charles Templeman), 1879-1940; Malinowski, Bronislaw, 1884-1942; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; South Africa. Native Affairs Commission; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale-China Association
- Correspondence, 1932, 1934-1940; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence includes letters, minutes, reports, and lists of publications. Folders are arranged alphabetically by name of individuals or institutions. Within each folder the material is then arranged chronologically. The correspondence is primarily with religious organizations, including Berkeley Divinity School, Hartford Seminary Foundation, Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, the World Sunday School Association, and several groups in China and the Pacific. Also included is information on the Phelps-Stokes Fund.
  - Berkeley Divinity School, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bernice P. Bishop Museum, Honolulu, Hawaii with minutes of meetings and list of publications, 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hartford Seminary Foundation, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hill, Richard Hurst, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - International Missionary Council, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kirby, Percival R., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lingnan University, Canton, China, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mark, Mary Louise, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Negro in America, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Phelps-Stokes Fund, with budget, estimated income, and proposed expenditure, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - World Sunday School Association, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yale-in-China, with minutes of meetings, reports, and notes on missions, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Writings, 1902-1940; Series II
  Writings include articles, reports, memoranda, book reviews, addresses, speeches, lectures, course and seminar outlines, college notebooks and notes, material from Boulder Seminar (1937), other people's writings, and theses written under Loram's supervision. Loram's articles, reports, speeches, lectures, course outlines and notes are arranged alphabetically by title. Loram's reviews and other people's writings are in alphabetical sequence by author's name.
  The writings relate to Christian missionary work, underprivileged people in foreign nations and the United States, race relations, educational systems, anthropological studies of various cultures and South Africa. The college notebooks and notes cover courses in language, psychology, history and law at Kings College, Cambridge University. The material from the Boulder Conference in July, 1947, concerns the American Indian.
  - Articles
    - "The Administration of Staff Among the Navajo", undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "The Anthropological Theory of Law", undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Can Jewish Emigrants Succeed in East and Central Africa?", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Christian Social Service and the Missionary", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Christianity and the Underprivileged Peoples", undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Church and Education in Mexico", undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Church and State in Indian Education in the United States and Canada" (Draft and three copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "The Crisis in American Education", undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "The Department of Race Relations at Yale University", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "The Devolution of Responsibility and Authority on Native Leaders" (2 copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "Does Uncle Sam Foster Paganism?", undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "East Africa and its Invaders from the Earliest Times to the Death of Seggid Said in 1856", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - "Education in the Union of South Africa", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "The Education of Backward Peoples, A Suggested Program" (2 copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "The Education of Indigenous Peoples" (2 copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "The Educational Situation in South Africa", undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "The Effects of Racial Contacts" (incomplete), undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - "Elements in the Cultural Heritage of the African which Contribute to the Achievement of Christian Personality", undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "England since October 21, 1933", undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "The Forerunners of the Conference" (draft and copy), undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Forerunners of the Hawaii-Yale Conference Seminar", undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Growth in Religious Education", undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Has the United States to Learn from Education in Other Lands?", undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - "The Influence of American Education Abroad", undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "The Jeanes Teachers in the United States", undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Lou Hofmeyr, Coordinator", undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "The Maori and Health", undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - "Marriage Among the Ama-Xosa" (3 copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Mexico, Past and Present", undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "The Missionary Government", undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "The Missions and the Race Problems", undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "A Nation in Transition", undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "A National System of Native Education in South Africa", undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "Native Administration in British South Africa", undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Navajo Education" (2 copies), undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "The Navajo Indian Problem", undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - "Notes on Secondary Education in Europe and the United States", undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "Overseas Students at Yale University", undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - "The Political and Financial Crisis in South Africa", undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - "Problems of Colonial Legislation and Administration with Special Reference to Africa", undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "Protectorate of South West Africa, Native Laws and Customs. Bushmen", undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - "Race Attitudes in South Africa", undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - "Race and Group Relationships as a University Study", undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - "Race Relations in Hawaii" (2 copies) and "Without Prejudice- The Race Situation in Hawaii", undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "Race Relationships as a Topic for Study in the Higher Classes of European Schools in South Africa", undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Religion and the Public School", undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Roman Catholic Missions in the United Sates" (2 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "Survey of Indian Missions in the United States" (2 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "Teacher Training Abroad", undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - "What Has the United States to Offer the Foreign Student?", undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Whither Japan and Why?", undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - "World Christianity and Indigenous Cultures", undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "Yale and China", undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Reports
    - "Christian Missions and the American Indians", undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - "Hua Chung College" (2 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - "Missionary Work in Puerto Rico", undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - "Native Christian Marriage", undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - "Native Life in South Africa", undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - "Native Marriages and Succession", undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Nigeria, Report on" (summary), undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - "Notes on Native Marriage Bill", undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - "Report on some Missions and Other Educational Institutions in Africa", undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - "Report on the Trip to Japan", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - "Summary of Viewpoint Regarding Christian Missionary Work in Portuguese Africa", undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Memoranda
    - "Research and Training in the Introduction of Western Civilization to Non-Western Peoples" (2 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - "On the Necessity for a Professorial Chair in Bantu Studies at the Naval University College", undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Book Reviews
    - Gulick, S. L., Toward Understanding Japan, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Jones, G. Howard, The Earth Goddess: A Study of Native Farming of the West African Coast, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Huxley, Julian, African View, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Lips, Julius E., The Savage Hits Back, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Maunier, Rene, Sociologie Coloniale Tome II Psychologie des Expansions, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Mott, John, World Citize n (3 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Newton, A. P. and E. A. Benian, The Cambridge History of the British Empire, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Raphael, Lois A. C., The Cape to Cairo Dream, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Westermann, Diedrich, Africa and Christianity, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Addresses and Speeches
    - The Cadets of Christ, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Character Education (6 copies), undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - The Christian Missionary and Indigenous Cultures, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Indigenous Cultures and the Missionary, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Intelligence in Missions, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - The Modern Missionary and His Work Today, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Some Corner Stones of American Education, undated (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Lectures
    - African Witch Doctors and Medicine Men, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Child Living and Learning, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - The Kazaks (outline), undated (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Native Education in the Union of South Africa, undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Soviet Nationalities, undated (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Course and Seminar Outlines
    - European Imperialism in Africa, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - History of Medicine, undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Japan, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Philosophy of Education, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Preparatory Schools and Private Universities, undated (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Race Relations, Seminar, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Suggestions for the Consideration of Students in Comparative Education, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - College Notebooks and Notes
    - Greek and Latin Composition, 1902-1904 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Educational Psychology, undated (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Greek History, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Greek History, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Roman History, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 112-113)
    - Literacy, undated (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Contracts, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Criminal Law, undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Criminal and Personal Property, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Real Property, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 118 - 120)
    - Real Property, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Roman Law
      - General, undated (Box 5, Folder 122)
      - Formal, Real, and Consensual Contracts, undated (Box 5, Folder 123)
      - Institute of, undated (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Torts, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Torts, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 126 - 127)
    - International Law, undated (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Law and Peace, undated (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Rights and Duties Respecting Equality, undated (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Boulder Seminar, 1937 July
    - Introductory Remarks, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Batty, Dr., "The New Curriculum for Indian Schools," "The Aims and Purposes of Indian Education", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Collier, John, "A Lecture on the American Indian", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Deloma, Rev. Vine J., "Christianity and the Indian" (3 copies), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Hubbard, Ralph, "An Outline of Indian-White Man History," "Special Problems of Indian Health", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Hulsizer, Allen, "Education in Undeveloped and Rural Communities", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Leh, Prof., "The Religious Genius of the Indian," "The Indian's Record Achievement", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - McGregor, Dr., "The Changing Californian", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - McKeel, Dr., "The Anthropological Approach to Indian Education," "Lecture on the American Indian", 1937 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Unidentified Lecturer, "The Indian and the Land,", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Unidentified lecturer, "Lecture on the American Indian", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - "The Changing American Indian", Summary of Proceedings, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Other People's Writings
    - Adams, Romanzo, "Education of the Part-Hawaiians", undated (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Alexander, William W., "Negroes in Rural America", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
      - "East Africa: Answers to the Questions Regarding Recommendations of the Inquiry Committee", undated (Box 7, Folder 145)
      - "Questions of Policy in the Africa Missions", undated (Box 7, Folder 145)
      - "Report on Rethinking Missions", undated (Box 7, Folder 145)
      - "Retrenchment Proposals of South Africa Mission", undated (Box 7, Folder 145)
      - "A Statement of Policy by the Africa Committee", 1934 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Ataloa, "The New Program of American Indian Education", undated (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Bacon, Elizabeth Emaline, "Physical Race Differences", undated (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Baker, Lucille, "Recreation or the Use of Leisure Time", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Ball, Douglas G., "Native Education in New Zealand", undated (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - Batchelder, J. E., Jr., "Health in China" and two book reviews and a memorandum, undated (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Bellegarde, Dantes
      - "The Economic Life of Haiti", undated (Box 7, Folder 151)
      - "History of Haitian People" by Winsor and Bellegarde, undated (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Bernard, G. A.
      - "Note on the Educational Policy of France in Indo-China", undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - "Educational Administration in French Indo-China", undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
      - "The Pagoda Schools of Cambodia", undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Bridgman, F. B., "A Contrast: Hampton and Howard", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Brown, G. Gordon
      - "The Native Teacher in Samoa", undated (Box 7, Folder 154)
      - "Education in American Samoa" (2 copies), undated (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - Brown, H. Maughan, "Report on Visit to America During 1929", 1930 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Brunk, Hazel H., "Territory of Hawaii" (outline), 1939 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Buck, Peter H., "The New Zealand Maori", undated (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Carpenter, George W.
      - "Education in the Congo and in the United States- A Study of Contrasts", 1935 (Box 7, Folder 158)
      - "Education for Health in the Congo", 1936 (Box 7, Folder 158)
      - "Education in the Belgian Congo", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Collier, John, "Hopi Marriages", 1934 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Devan, S. Arthur, "The Religion of the Negro", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Downs, Sophie W., "The Foreign Education Digest", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Elkin, A. P., "The Changing Aborigine with Special Reference to Education", undated (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Faine, Jules, "Formation of the Creole Language", undated (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Franz, G. H., "Making Stories", undated (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Fryer, E. R., "Report on the Navajo Indians", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Griffiths, J. "Customs Observed by the Zulu", 1929 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Groves, William C., "Education and the New Guinea Background", undated (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Guingona, Teopisto, "Report on the Non-Christian Tribes in the Philippines", 1935 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - Helfant, Mary Linda, "Race Relations", 1939 (Box 8, Folder 169)
    - Herskovits, M. J., "Outline on Family", undated (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Holt, W. E., "Notes on Education in Nigeria", 1937 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Hrdlicka, Ales, "Human Evolution", 1925 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Joardan, N., "Buddhism", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - Johnson, Guy B., "Graduate Study for Southern Negro Students", undated (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Jones, Thomas Jesse, Radio Talk (WABC) "What Is Education", 1933 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Kay, W., "Higher Education in Hong Kong", undated (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - Keesing, Felix M., "Education in Pacific Countries", 1936 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Klotzberger, Edward L., "Secondary Education and the Social Order", undated (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Leh, Leonard L., "The Indian's Record Achievement", "The Religious Genius of the Indian", undated (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Loram, Ian Craig, "Race Relations", 1939 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - McCormick, J. Scott
      - "The Language Problem in Philippine Education, undated (Box 8, Folder 181)
      - "Education in the Philippines" (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - McKay, C., "Native life in Western Samoa", undated (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Malherbe, E. G., "Our Human Resources", 1931 (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - Mann, Winifred E., "The Use of the Vernacular as the Medium of Instruction in the Elementary Schools of the Philippine Islands", undated (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - Matthews, Z. K.
      - "Health and the Bantu in the Union of South South Africa", undated (Box 8, Folder 185)
      - "The History of Medicine" (Box 8, Folder 185)
      - "The Impact of Western Civilization in Native Law in South Africa" (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Maude, Henry E., "Culture Change and Education in the Gilbert and Ellice Islands", undated (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - May, Don, "Tentative Classroom Program for the Shiprock Navajo Agricultural High School", 1938 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Mayhew, Arthur I., "Educational Policy in the British Colonial Empire", undated (Box 9, Folder 188)
    - Mellen, Kathleen Dickinson, "Ukelele Politics", undated (Box 9, Folder 189)
    - Merrill, Doris P., "Experiments in Educating for Living", 1935 (Box 9, Folder 190)
    - Metraux, Alfred, "South America: Blend of Peoples and Cultures", undated (Box 9, Folder 191)
    - Midkiff, Frank E., "Review of Ancient and Modern Medical Practices in Hawaii", 1933 (Box 9, Folder 192)
    - Miller, H. S., "The Westernization of India", 1938 (Box 9, Folder 193)
    - Mukasa, Balamu, J., "Education in Uganda", 1937 (Box 9, Folder 194)
    - Ner, Marcel
      - "Essay on the Philosophy of Education in French Indo-China", undated (Box 9, Folder 195)
      - "Education and the Social System in French Indo-China" (Box 9, Folder 195)
    - Oshima, Masanori, "Present Education Problems of Japan", undated (Box 9, Folder 196)
    - Oshima, Masanori, and R. Nakaseko, "Higher Education", undated (Box 9, Folder 197)
    - Oshima, Masanori and R. Nakaseko, "Japan: Modern Educational System", undated (Box 9, Folder 198)
    - Oshima, Masanori, and R. Nakaseko, "Japan: Modernizing an Oriental People", undated (Box 9, Folder 199)
    - Phillips, Ray E., "Bantu-White Adjustment" (outline), undated (Box 9, Folder 200)
    - Price-Mars, Dr., "Ethnic Formation and Folklore of Haiti", undated (Box 9, Folder 201)
    - Radcliffe-Brown, Dr., Social Sciences Lectures Delivered at Yale Summer Seminar, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 202)
    - Ramos, Arthur, "The Negro in Brazil", 1939 (Box 9, Folder 203)
    - Reyneke, J., "African Education and the Missionary", undated (Box 9, Folder 204)
    - Ross, Johan J., "The Mexican System of Education", 1937 (Box 9, Folder 205)
    - Rutherford, D. A. J., "Education in Western Samoa", undated (Box 9, Folder 206)
    - Sanchez, George I., "Mexico: A Revolution Through Education", undated (Box 9, Folder 207)
    - Williams, F. E., "Education in Papua", undated (Box 9, Folder 208)
    - Wisdom, R. H. W., "Education in Kenya", 1937 (Box 9, Folder 209)
    - Wrong, Margaret, "Memorandum on the Expansion of the Work of the International Committee on Christian Literature for Africa", 1934 (Box 9, Folder 210)
    - "The Concordat between the Holy See and the Republic of Haiti", "Notes on the Concordat", undated (Box 9, Folder 211)
    - Education in Chile (bibliography), 1937 (Box 9, Folder 212)
    - "Education of African Chiefs", undated (Box 9, Folder 213)
    - Education of the Maori, undated (Box 9, Folder 214)
    - "Justice", undated (Box 9, Folder 215)
    - "Native Education in Kanya", undated (Box 9, Folder 216)
    - "The New Deal in the Union of South Africa", undated (Box 9, Folder 217)
    - The Philippine Literacy Method [typescript by an unidentified author], undated (Box 9, Folder 218)
    - Report on the Jeanes School in Kenya, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - A Study of Techniques in Areas of High Illiteracy with Special Reference to Adults, undated (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations, Report of Advisor Tour of Ciskei, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - University of Hong Kong, Teaching Chinese Studies, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - Writings and Phonetics of Zulu Sounds, undated (Box 10, Folder 223)